<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Baigel Bytes</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Baigel Bytes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Myamoto - Wisdom of The Ages (Part 2).</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/wota2miyamoto/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/wota2miyamoto/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;first-an-introduction-to-the-series-wisdom-of-the-ages&#34;&gt;First, an introduction to the series. Wisdom of the ages:&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Those who fail to learn from history are doomed to repeat it.”&lt;/strong&gt; - Winston Churchill.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is true, not just for societies and cultures at large, across centuries and millennia, but across decades, years, months and days in and throughout our own individual lives.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you fail to learn from the mistakes of your past, you will keep repeating them and they will, time and time again, halt your progress forward, upwards, to becoming a better version of yourself.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aristotle - Wisdom of the ages (part 1).</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/aristotle/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/aristotle/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;first-an-introduction-to-the-series-wisdom-of-the-ages&#34;&gt;First, an introduction to the series. Wisdom of the ages:&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“Those who fail to learn from history are doomed to repeat it.” - Winston Churchill.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is true, not just for societies and cultures at large, across centuries and millennia, but across decades, years, months and days in and throughout our own individual lives.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you fail to learn from the mistakes of your past, you will keep repeating them and they will, time and time again, halt your progress forward, upwards, to becoming a better version of yourself.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Buddha In The Storm</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/tbits/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/tbits/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One day some years ago I asked myself, what would the enlightened version of me look like? I imagined another version of me in a Buddhist monks robes, sitting down meditating in front of a white picket fence with a tornado raging around me.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Despite that tornado being there and being very capable of killing me, this Enlightened version of me just sat there calm as anything, meditating.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now I have already mentioned this Buddha in the storm in &lt;a href=&#34;https://baigelbytes.netlify.app/blog/mh2/&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; post but this superpower is just to great not to share again.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Journey Of A Thousand Steps.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/tjoats/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/tjoats/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How do you start making progress towards any goal?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;The journey of a thousand steps starts with just a single one.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Start. That&amp;rsquo;s it. Thats the first step. That&amp;rsquo;s how you get going in the direction of your goals. You will make mistakes, you will fall and break and maybe even cheat but you will also get back up and moving forward again.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Forward, towards the end but focus on the getting there because that&amp;rsquo;s where half the living is.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>More mental and physical health tips from journeys past &amp; present.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/mh2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/mh2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction:&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Have you ever woken up from sleep with a sharp pain in your ear? One so sharp, so intense that you can&amp;rsquo;t even lift your head off the pillow without quietly (so as not to wake your flatmates) shreeking in pain.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is something that&amp;rsquo;s happend to me many times and continues to happen to me to this day. I&amp;rsquo;ll have to look into it sometime but for now I&amp;rsquo;m using it as part of the inspiration for this article.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vegans, why calling people murderers and rapists isn&#39;t the best way to get them to listen to your arguments.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/vegans/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/vegans/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;reason-cannot-be-cultivated-in-a-mind-consumed-by-emotions&#34;&gt;Reason cannot be cultivated in a mind consumed by emotions.&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yes, I agree with the ethics and moral standing of the vegan argument. It is not right to take the lives of sentient beings that have the same desire as us to enjoy life and procreate. Yes, I and many other meat eaters agree that factory farming is abhorent at the very least and alternatives methods of cultivating animal based protiens, if people insist upon or require them for health reasons, need to be devised and implimented. Methods that cause no harm to animals and do not require them to be kept in the conditions they are.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>There is no center of the Universe! (Topics I can&#39;t compute - part 2)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/ticc2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/ticc2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is part 2 in the series, Topics I can&amp;rsquo;t compute. As the name sugguests this series deals with topics I either partially or completely don&amp;rsquo;t understand or that are so mind blowing that I find them hard to wrap my head around. Hopefully your brains don&amp;rsquo;t get completely fried XD. Enjoy :)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;are-you-ready-to-have-your-mind-blown&#34;&gt;Are you ready to have your mind blown?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Our entire universe could be the 3 dimensional surface of a four dimensional hypersphere!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Capitalism. Where anyone can become rich, but not everyone.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/capitalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/capitalism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-the-rich-get-richer-and-the-poor-get-poorer&#34;&gt;Why the rich get richer and the poor get poorer:&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;its-not-exclusively-the-governments-fault&#34;&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not exclusively the governments fault:&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Not &lt;strong&gt;exclusivley&lt;/strong&gt; I said!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yes its a fact, a frustratingly sad fact that a lot of the richest people in the world pay little to no taxes. I agree this is absolutely not ok and should change so they start giving their fair share!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, we - and I include myself in this - are also at least partly to blame. We are the ones who keep throwing money at the billionares! What do people do when there&amp;rsquo;s a new iphone out? &amp;ldquo;OH MY GOD TAKE MY LIFE SAVINGS NOOOOWWWWWWW!!!!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Arguments for the possibility of a created universe.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/deismpossible/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/deismpossible/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-i-think-scientists-and-atheists-shouldnt-say-there-cant-be-a-god-or-that-there-definitely-isnt-one&#34;&gt;Why I think scientists and atheists shouldn&amp;rsquo;t say there can&amp;rsquo;t be a God or that there definitely isn&amp;rsquo;t one.&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction:&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One thing that religious people often say is &amp;lsquo;There just has to be a creator&amp;rsquo;. Atheists will be quick to point out that this isn&amp;rsquo;t technically true. But some atheists commit the same mistake when they (sometimes proudly) proclaim that their is no god or that nothing happens after we die besides us going into the ground and our bodies getting eaten by insects.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Free will might just be an illusion! (Topics I can&#39;t compute - part 1)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/freewill/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/freewill/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is part one of a series called: Topics I can&amp;rsquo;t compute. As the name sugguests posts in this series will cover topics that I either partially or completely don&amp;rsquo;t understand or that are so mind blowing that I find them hard to wrap my head around.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;free-will-vs-determinism&#34;&gt;Free Will vs Determinism.&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-thought-experiment&#34;&gt;A thought experiment:&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Is free will real? Some philosophers think not.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Think of your favourite food, let&amp;rsquo;s say for example you absolutely love steak! Think about how you feel about steak, how you feel when you&amp;rsquo;re eating a really REALLY good one. Now, think of your least favourite food. Let&amp;rsquo;s say it&amp;rsquo;s cauliflower for example.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
