<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SeriesName on Baigel Bytes</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/series/seriesname/</link>
    <description>Recent content in SeriesName on Baigel Bytes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/series/seriesname/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Myamoto - Wisdom of The Ages (Part 2).</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/wota2miyamoto/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/wota2miyamoto/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;first-an-introduction-to-the-series-wisdom-of-the-ages&#34;&gt;First, an introduction to the series. Wisdom of the ages:&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Those who fail to learn from history are doomed to repeat it.”&lt;/strong&gt; - Winston Churchill.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is true, not just for societies and cultures at large, across centuries and millennia, but across decades, years, months and days in and throughout our own individual lives.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you fail to learn from the mistakes of your past, you will keep repeating them and they will, time and time again, halt your progress forward, upwards, to becoming a better version of yourself.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aristotle - Wisdom of the ages (part 1).</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/aristotle/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/aristotle/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;first-an-introduction-to-the-series-wisdom-of-the-ages&#34;&gt;First, an introduction to the series. Wisdom of the ages:&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“Those who fail to learn from history are doomed to repeat it.” - Winston Churchill.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is true, not just for societies and cultures at large, across centuries and millennia, but across decades, years, months and days in and throughout our own individual lives.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you fail to learn from the mistakes of your past, you will keep repeating them and they will, time and time again, halt your progress forward, upwards, to becoming a better version of yourself.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>More mental and physical health tips from journeys past &amp; present.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/mh2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/mh2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction:&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Have you ever woken up from sleep with a sharp pain in your ear? One so sharp, so intense that you can&amp;rsquo;t even lift your head off the pillow without quietly (so as not to wake your flatmates) shreeking in pain.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is something that&amp;rsquo;s happend to me many times and continues to happen to me to this day. I&amp;rsquo;ll have to look into it sometime but for now I&amp;rsquo;m using it as part of the inspiration for this article.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vegans, why calling people murderers and rapists isn&#39;t the best way to get them to listen to your arguments.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/vegans/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/vegans/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;reason-cannot-be-cultivated-in-a-mind-consumed-by-emotions&#34;&gt;Reason cannot be cultivated in a mind consumed by emotions.&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yes, I agree with the ethics and moral standing of the vegan argument. It is not right to take the lives of sentient beings that have the same desire as us to enjoy life and procreate. Yes, I and many other meat eaters agree that factory farming is abhorent at the very least and alternatives methods of cultivating animal based protiens, if people insist upon or require them for health reasons, need to be devised and implimented. Methods that cause no harm to animals and do not require them to be kept in the conditions they are.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Capitalism. Where anyone can become rich, but not everyone.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/capitalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/capitalism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-the-rich-get-richer-and-the-poor-get-poorer&#34;&gt;Why the rich get richer and the poor get poorer:&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;its-not-exclusively-the-governments-fault&#34;&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not exclusively the governments fault:&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Not &lt;strong&gt;exclusivley&lt;/strong&gt; I said!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yes its a fact, a frustratingly sad fact that a lot of the richest people in the world pay little to no taxes. I agree this is absolutely not ok and should change so they start giving their fair share!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, we - and I include myself in this - are also at least partly to blame. We are the ones who keep throwing money at the billionares! What do people do when there&amp;rsquo;s a new iphone out? &amp;ldquo;OH MY GOD TAKE MY LIFE SAVINGS NOOOOWWWWWWW!!!!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Arguments for the possibility of a created universe.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/deismpossible/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/deismpossible/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-i-think-scientists-and-atheists-shouldnt-say-there-cant-be-a-god-or-that-there-definitely-isnt-one&#34;&gt;Why I think scientists and atheists shouldn&amp;rsquo;t say there can&amp;rsquo;t be a God or that there definitely isn&amp;rsquo;t one.&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction:&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One thing that religious people often say is &amp;lsquo;There just has to be a creator&amp;rsquo;. Atheists will be quick to point out that this isn&amp;rsquo;t technically true. But some atheists commit the same mistake when they (sometimes proudly) proclaim that their is no god or that nothing happens after we die besides us going into the ground and our bodies getting eaten by insects.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mental Health Issues, some Self Help Tips.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/mh/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/mh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction:&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Disclaimer:&lt;/em&gt; I am not a medical professional. The points of advice I&amp;rsquo;m about to give in this article are not medical advice, if you are experiencing symptoms of any medical conditions please seek professional advice from your GP. The tips I list below can however be used in addition to any professional medical advice you recieve from your doctor so long as they approve. Thank you :)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Considering all of the near infinite crazyness that&amp;rsquo;s been happening over the last decade (I&amp;rsquo;m reffering off course to that year that shall not be named which felt like a decade.), I think it&amp;rsquo;s fair to say that just about everyone has experienced some form of mental health issue or trauma. Whether it was depression, anxiety, stress or the loss of a loved one. I want you, the person reading this article right now to know, there is help available and you are 100% capable of getting through this!!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
